# LILLIAN MIIRI

Telephone: +254706118319 Lmiiri95@gmail.com

I am a Product Manager with 5+ years of experience in Telecommunications, Digital Payments, Internet connectivity, Entertainment and Consumer IoT. I have a track record of driving strategic projects and leading high-performing teams to identify unmet customer needs and commercialization opportunities. I am passionate about user experience and using technology to bring equality.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

SAFARICOM PLC Nairobi Kenya

#### Product Manager-Safaricom Home Fibre Base Growth

April 2022 – present

- Strategically negotiated a partnership with Multichoice, leading a cross-functional team to successfully deliver Showmax products on USSD and mobile app platforms.
- Implemented an agile approach, resulting in a Minimum Viable Product for Home Insurance by paring down feature list by 60% thus accelerating critical development, and improving time-to-market.
- Spearheaded the groundbreaking launch of 5G technology in Kenya, positioning Safaricom as the pioneer and driving a significant 50% increase in network speeds..
- Managed P&L for 150K+ Fibre customers through reporting and analyzing financials against set metrics.

## **Product Manager- Fixed Data**

April 2021 - March 2022

- Orchestrated cross-functional collaboration among UX, engineering, sales, and digital marketing teams to achieve 115% yearly target for acquiring new customers by launching three campaigns.
- Reduced Home Fibre installation time by 75% through building an App currently used by 5000+ agents.
- Developed a user-centric roadmap, leading a team of six engineers to design and implement a new digital onboarding process, resulting in a 15-point increase in customer NPS within six months.
- Implemented automation initiatives, collaborating with four vendors to improve new customer provisioning success rate by 36%..
- Collaborated with 4 analysts to conduct user research, product testing, interviews, and surveys on 1000+ Fixed internet customers to ensure product changes meet the customer needs.

#### Product Manager/Product Owner- Fixed LTE and Public Wi-Fi

February 2020 - March 2021

- Grew LTE sales by 47% through formulating the dealer sales model and driving acceptance and adoption with various stakeholders.
- Conducted user research on 20,000 + customers and led an agile team to build LTE plans that delivered Ksh 157M revenue on the first year
- Defined a comprehensive product strategy for alternative connectivity, delivering a remarkable 60% increase in Average Revenue per Account (ARPA).
- Collaborated with Facebook and Nokia to successfully deploy Public Wi-Fi hotspots in 50 low-income areas, driving a substantial 120% increase in ARPA.
- Reduced LTE customer registration time by 93% through leading design and development for LTE sales portal that improved user onboarding experience

#### Senior Product Officer – Home and Consumer IoT

September 2019 – January 2020

Led a successful technical and commercial pilot of 4G for Home Plans with 523 customers by constantly
analyzing metrics, market trends, and competitive landscapes to ensure optimal performance and
competitiveness.

- Achieved 250% customer base growth in 2 months by leading product development priorities, GTM and sales strategy for the commercial launch of 4G for home plans
- Led the redesign of Home App from ideation, assignment to execution by working with Android and iOS product teams to prioritize features thus reducing demand by 15%.
- Collaborated with a team of 6 analysts to analyze market conditions, competitor strategies and untapped user needs in 5 counties, resulting in 2 new products.

#### Graduate Management Trainee

April 2018 – August 2019

Successfully completed an 18- month cross-functional structured program while undertaking various projects within the business. Some of the key achievements include:

- Saved the company Ksh 334 Mn+ annually in Sim recycling costs by leading pilot and commercial launch of a new Dynamic SIM Card allocation method.
- Accomplished 50% SIM Card price reduction by negotiating with vendors and working with supply chain to remove unnecessary packaging elements resulting in 42% increase in acquisitions.
- Conducted market research and business analysis on new developments in the industry presenting the findings weekly to EXCO team to influence key strategic decisions.
- Collaboratively worked with an agile team to redesign consumer mobile data propositions with Free WhatsApp that increased monthly revenue by 200 million+.
- Improved customer satisfaction and brand love by 24% by designing the idea of 1GB data bundle to be allocated to each of 27 million customers on their birthday.

#### CYTONN INVESTMENTS COMPANY

Legal Assistant (02/2017) - (03/2018)

Responsible for safeguarding Cytonn, its clients and assets, by driving compliance with applicable laws, rules and regulations, adhering to Policy, applying sound ethical judgment regarding personal behavior, conduct and business practices.

- Led the initiative to digitize legal documentation leading to 50% reduction in SLA
- Designed and led development of a web portal for 9 board members to digitize board voting.
- Ensured company wide legal compliance by reviewing legislative changes to ensure readiness
- Managed 2 legal interns learning process by curating a learning path and skills assessment.

# PEMA SELF HELP GROUP

## **Project Assistant**

(02/2012) - (04/2013)

Pema is an NGO funded by Fairtrade to run community projects in Thika region. My role was to develop a forl and comprehensive project plan by integrating and documenting project deliverables, acceptance criteria, processes, procedures, risks, and tasks to facilitate project execution, controlling, and closing processes.

# **EDUCATION**

**DEGREE**:Software Engineering (2023), BSc Industrial Chemistry (University of Nairobi,2017)

**COURSES:** Data Engineering Micro master - Moringa School(2023),

CERTIFICATIONS: AWS Cloud Practitioner, Certified Scrum Product Owner(CSPO), Prince 2 Practitioner

**TECHNICAL SKILLS:** Python, SQL, Advanced Excel, C, R, HTML, CSS, firebase, Project Management, Agile Product Development(managing sprints and backlog grooming.), Scrum, Go-To- Market Strategy, Data analytics tools(Qlik, Firebase).